Sushant Bhat

+1(201)724-5819 | sush1393@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/sushantbhat93/ | github.com/bhatsushant | Jersey City, NJ-07307

SUMMARY

Experienced Full Stack Developer with 4 years of industry expertise, consistently delivering robust web applications and exceptional user experiences to 10+ clients. Committed to contributing my skills to a collaborative team, while continuously expanding my knowledge in this rapidly evolving field. Actively pursuing a challenging role that nurtures innovation and promotes ongoing professional development.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer Intern - breathing.ai

Sep 2023 - Present

- Optimizing API redirection to enhance consumer feedback management, utilizing Loopback framework
- Mitigating critical concerns like URL injection restricting extension access to unnecessary file paths, employing Node.js

Graduate Teaching Assistant - Stevens Institute of Technology

- Employed the Ticketmaster and Pokemon APIs to develop Ticketmaster clone and Pokemon-catching applications respectively, serving as instructional tools to introduce React.js, Redux.js concepts to over 100 students
- Structured a Pinterest clone leveraging GraphQL to facilitate the storage and uploading of 100+ local and online images to Redis
- Conducted comprehensive tutoring sessions for 140+ students while grading 200+ assignments and 10+ projects improving conceptual understanding and proficiency in building applications

Full Stack Developer - Freelance

Jul 2019 - Jul 2021

- Spearheaded digital transformation of an air-conditioner business, developing a website that attracted local buyers and boosted sales by 50%, surpassing the limitations of the paper-based system implementing HTML5, CSS3 and JS
- Implemented Bootstrap and JQuery to create an interactive dashboard for a financial firm to track loan collection amounts, total loans issued, assets and debt statistics for 50+ debtors leading in 20% increase in loan issuance

Associate Software Engineer - CRISIL Ltd.

Jan 2017 - Jul 2019

- Developed FULKRUM product (similar to Oracle Business Intelligence) for creating dashboards implementing Angular.js, Java, JQuery, and SQL for wholesale banking customers helping the users extract crucial data for decision making
- Engineered a 10-level performance rating portal for Senior Regional Managers to analyze consumer feedback in various regions resulting in better customer interactivity across regions
- Effectively led a 5-intern team in developing an Access Control module for various access and authorization activities using Firebase, resulting in streamlined security protocols and enhanced user data protection

ACADEMIC / PERSONAL PROJECTS

House of Books Feb 2022 - May 2022

- Designed the user interface for a digital bookstore, leveraging React, Express, MongoDB, and Sass, seamlessly integrating cart functionality employing **Redux** for managing purchases and rentals of over 500 books
- Leveraged Netlify to streamline the online hosting of the application's frontend, minimizing the need for users to download, install, and run local resources, enhancing user convenience

MediaHub Aug 2021 - Dec 2021

- Engineered a review system to rate over 100+ movies and shows to help users plan their watchlist using Express.js and MongoDB
- Designed a user profile component, offering personalized experiences with options to manage details and wish-lists using React.js

LEADERSHIP EXPERIENCE / AWARDS AND NOMINATIONS / ACHIEVEMENTS

- Coordinated with external speakers to organize tech events and hackathons as Google Developer Student Clubs Secretary
- Mentored Stevens students, offering academic guidance and facilitating their adjustment to campus while providing essential information for a successful and swift acclimatization to life in the U.S.
- Earned the "Customer Delight Award" and "Breakthrough Initiative Award" from CRISIL Ltd. for speedy resolution of issues

EDUCATION

Master of Science in Computer Science

Aug 2021 - May 2023

Stevens Institute of Technology

Aug 2014 - May 2017

Master of Science in Computer Application University of Mumbai

Aug 2011 - May 2014

Bachelor of Science in Information Technology

University of Mumbai

SKILLS

Programming / Markup languages: JavaScript, Python, SQL, HTML5, CSS3

Frameworks / Libraries: React.js, Redux.js, Express.js, Node.js MongoDB, Redis, GraphQL, Bootstrap, Sass, Styled Components